<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cel76</title>
    <description>queuing in line since 1976</description>
    <link>http://cel76.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cel76.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:59:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Boogie Down Productions</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AmlwCEEh37s?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BDP’s 4th album ‘Edutainment’ was the 2nd album I ever purchased after being handed a crappy cassette recording of ‘Ghetto Music: The Blueprint of Hip Hop’ when I was 13/14 years old. I was drawn to the raw minimal production values, funk samples, jamaican musical influences, beatboxing, and to an extent for a 13 year old the outspoken, defiant, socially conscious lyrics. 
Written and produced by BDPs only constant member KRS-One, ‘Jack of Spades’ is about a vigilante trying to clean up his neighbourhood whilst paid-off police look on. It uses a sample from Jamaican funk band Brentford Allstars’ dub cover of James Brown’s ‘Get on the Good Foot’, ‘Greedy G’. It was included on the soundtrack to the 1988 blaxploitation parody ‘I’m Gonna Git You Sucka’ and the music video contains clips from said film. It went to number 3 in the US Rap charts in ’88 but more importantly appeared on that crappy cassette recording I was handed in 1990.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 15:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cel76.com/music/2018/04/29/BDP-Jack-Of-Spades.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cel76.com/music/2018/04/29/BDP-Jack-Of-Spades.html</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paul Weller</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYAwhFrZADs?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard this Paul Weller remix on the Future Sound of London’s legendary December 1993 Essential Mix on BBC Radio 1. FSOL broadcasted live from their Earthbeat studio via ISDN into the BBC Studios. Their combination of sound, visuals and technology were cutting edge and incredibly exciting at the time. If you haven’t heard it, you can hear the entire broadcast on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mixcloud.com/DJ_Mix/future-sound-of-london-fsol-essential-mix-1993-12-04/&quot;&gt;MixCloud&lt;/a&gt;.
To me it’s timeless. The track was remixed by Paul Weller’s long time producer Brendan Lynch, known for his experimental dub remixes as a side hobby to his regular pop/rock productions. With the internet in it’s infancy (Netscape didn’t even exist until 1994), tracklist information was hard to come by in those days. I only discovered the record by chance at a free party in a field at dawn in the middle of nowhere in Somerset, played out by some hippie funk acquaintances who ran nights called ‘The Dig In’ on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theklabristol.co.uk&quot;&gt;boat&lt;/a&gt; in Bristol. Fun times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 15:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cel76.com/music/2018/04/28/Paul-Weller-Kosmos-(Lynch-Mob-Bonus-Beats-Remix).html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cel76.com/music/2018/04/28/Paul-Weller-Kosmos-(Lynch-Mob-Bonus-Beats-Remix).html</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pet Shop Boys</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKl6-fpW7_o?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a young teenager in the mid to late Eighties I was a big fan of the Pet Shop Boys. I was drawn to their fusion of Hi-NRG and electro influences with strong melodies. I admired their refusal to conform to the standard pop act format and the resoluteness of their principals. Their reluctance to perform on stage or be interviewed created a certain mysticism and intrigue. Throughout the decade they consistently had remixes of their music produced by unknown artists such as Arthur Baker, Junior Vasquez, Francois Kervorkian, Tyree, Marshall Jefferson, Sterling Void as well as Brothers in Rhythm and KLF which ultimately led me to the discovery of a whole new underground music scene I never knew existed. Two Divided By Zero is the opening track on their first album entitled ‘Please’. It has their early trademark electro drums, synth basslines and features a talking calculator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 15:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cel76.com/music/2018/04/12/Pet-Shop-Boys-Two-Divided-by-Zero.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cel76.com/music/2018/04/12/Pet-Shop-Boys-Two-Divided-by-Zero.html</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
